(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-19T22:41:32.980498",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
MUSIC GARDEN TAKANE LUI Birthday Live 2025!
はい 尾丸ポルカでーす よろしくお願いいたします
Hi, I'm Omaru Polka. Pleased to be here!
こんばんは 司会の白上フブキです よろしくお願いいたします
Good evening! I'm your host, Shirakami Fubuki! Nice to meet you all!
さて 今夜も始まりました MUSIC GARDENでございますけども
Now, tonight marks another edition of MUSIC GARDEN...
なんか久々だね
It's been a while, hasn't it?
はい 約２年ぶりに復活...
Yes, making a comeback after about two years...
というわけでですね、
And so,
あ、復活。おめでたいね。
Oh, the revival! Congratulations!
そうですね。
Yes, indeed.
髪切った？
Did you cut your hair?
あ、切ってないんですけど。ルイ姉様もそんなこと言ってましたね。
Ah, I didn't. But Lui-nesama was saying that too!
そうだっけ？
Did she really?
そうですよ！ポルカさんもお変わりなく...
Yes, she did! And you haven't changed either, Polka-san...
まあ、はい。元気でやってるわ。
Well, yes. I'm doing great.
それはよかったです。ポルカさんの元気にも負けないくらい、今回元気なゲストさんもいますので。
That's good to hear. We have some very energetic guests today who won't lose to your energy!
うん、それは楽しみだね。
Yeah, I'm looking forward to that.
はい。では早速紹介していきましょう。本日のゲストの登場です！
Alright, let's introduce them right away. Here come today's guests!
音乃瀬奏！
Otonose Kanade!
猫又おかゆ！
Nekomata Okayu!
大神ミオ！
Ookami Mio!
百鬼あやめ！
Nakiri Ayame!
鷹嶺ルイ！
Takane Lui!
今夜も豪華ゲストでお送りするミュージックガーデン。なんと今夜は、
Tonight's Music Garden features a gorgeous guest lineup! And tonight...
あっと驚くような仕掛けいっぱいでお送りするみたいですよ。最後まで見逃せません！
...it seems we have lots of surprising gimmicks in store. Don't miss it till the very end!
ああー、どんな仕掛けなんだろうね。鷹嶺ルイくん。
Oh, I wonder what kind of gimmicks those are. Takane Lui-kun?
はい。
Yes?
ミュージックガーデンと言えば鷹嶺ルイくんだから。今日は誕生日ということで。
Speaking of Music Garden, it has to be you. And since today is your birthday...
はい、ありがとうございます。そうなんです、今日誕生日なんですよ。
Yes, thank you! That's right, today is my birthday!
２年ぶりに復活したけど、どう？緊張してる？
We're back after two years! How are you feeling? Nervous?
はい、緊張してます。でも復活にふさわしい場にできるんじゃないかなと思っているので、楽しみにしていてください。
Yes, I'm nervous. But I think I can make this stage worthy of the revival, so please look forward to it!
なんか匂いますね。
I smell something...
え？ちゃんとお風呂入ってきた？
Eh? Did you take a proper bath?
その匂いじゃないです！それじゃないですよ。
Not that kind of smell! That's not what I meant!
あ、そっかそっか。
Ah, right, right.
今日は一曲目の披露だよね？
Today you'll perform your first song, right?
はい、このあとすぐに披露させていただきます。
Yes, I'll be performing it right after this.
はい、一曲目は鷹嶺ルイさんに、アニメの主題歌でも話題でした「BOW AND ARROW」を披露していただきます。
Alright! For the first song, Takane Lui-san will perform "BOW AND ARROW", which became a hot topic as an anime theme song!
ほう。あのフィギュアスケートの？
Oh, the one associated with figure skating?
はい。今回は特別にフィギュアスケート風のダンスを踊ってくださるダンサーさんと一緒にパフォーマンスをさせていただきます。
Yes. This time, I will perform with a dancer who will specially perform a figure skating-style dance!
ほう、それは楽しみだな。
Oh, I look forward to that.
そうですね。それではスタンバイの方よろしくお願いします。
Indeed. Well then, please get on standby.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, thank you.
ねえ、あれ猫又くんと音乃瀬くんと大神くん、あ、初登場だっけ？
Hey, are Nekomata-kun, Otonose-kun, and Ookami-kun making their first appearance?
そうですよ！
That's right!
音乃瀬くん、緊張してるんじゃない？
Otonose-kun, aren't you nervous?
もう、全然大丈夫ですよ！いけます！
I'm completely fine! I can do this!
元気だね。
So energetic!
元気ですね。
She's so lively.
そして二回目の登場が百鬼くん。
And making her second appearance is Nakiri-kun.
はい、お久しぶりです！
Yes, it's been a while!
そういえば、シュークリーム食べた？
By the way, did you eat cream puffs?
え、ちょっと今日、まだ... まだ今日食べてないんです。
Eh? Actually, today, I... I hasn't eaten them yet today.
あ、そっかそっか。まあ後でね、ゆっくりね、食べてね。
Ah, I see, I see. Well, you can eat them slowly later.
はい、いっぱい食べます！
Yes, I'll eat a lot of them!
のちほど皆様ともゆっくりお話しさせていただこうと思います。
We'll have a chance to chat slowly with everyone later.
さて、スタンバイができたみたいですね。
Now, it looks like she is on standby.
アニメをリスペクトしたダンスにもご注目ください。
Please pay attention to the dance that respects the anime.
鷹嶺ルイで、「BOW AND ARROW」。
Here is Takane Lui with "BOW AND ARROW"!
気づけば靴は汚れ 錆びついた諸刃を伝う雨
Before I knew it, my shoes were soiled, and rain dripped down the rusted double-edged blade.
憧れはそのままで 夢から目覚めた先には夢
With my yearnings left as they are, waking up from a dream only led to another dream.
聞こえたその泣き声 消え入る手前のノブレスオブリージュ
I heard that crying voice, a noblesse oblige right on the verge of fading away.
憧れのその先へ うずくまる君を見つける為
Beyond that yearning, in order to find you crouching there.
行け 行け 追いつけない速度で 飛べ インパルス加速して
Go, go, at an unreachable speed; fly, accelerating your impulses.
インパルス加速して
...accelerating my impulses
行け きっとこの時を感じる為に
Go, surely to feel this very moment
生まれてきたんだ
I was born into this world
未来を掴んで 期待値を超えて
Seizing the future, exceeding all expectations
額に吹き刺す風
With the wind blowing against my forehead
今に見よきっと君の眩しさに
Just wait and see, surely at your radiance
誰もが気づくだろう
everyone will soon take notice
相応しい声で 視線追い越して
With a fitting voice, overtaking all glances
虚空を超えて行け
Go beyond the empty void
見違えていく君の指から今
Right now, from your fingers that look so different
手を放す
I let go of your hand
気づけば謎は解かれ
Before I knew it, the mystery was solved
木目ごと見慣れた板の上
On top of these familiar wooden stage planks
あの頃焦がれたような
Have I managed to become
大人になれたかな
The kind of adult I longed to be back then?
そう君の苦悩は
Yes, your suffering
君が自分で選んだ痛みだ
Is a pain you chose for yourself
そして掴んだあの煌めきも
And that sparkle you grasped
全て君のものだ
Is entirely yours
僕は弓になって
I became a bow
君の白んだ掌をとって強く引いた
Taking your pale hand and pulling back with all my might
今君は決して
Now, you have become an arrow
風に流れない矢になって
That will never be swept away by the wind
行け 行け 決して振り向かないで
Go, go, never look back
飛べ もう届かない場所へ
Fly, to a place far beyond reach
行け 行け 君はいつだって
Go, go, you were always
輝いていた
Shining so brightly
未来を掴んで 期待値を超えて
Seizing the future, exceeding all expectations
額に吹き刺す風
With the wind blowing against my forehead
今に見よきっと君の眩しさに
Just wait and see, surely at your radiance
誰もが気づくだろう
everyone will soon take notice
相応しい声で 視線追い越して
With a fitting voice, overtaking all glances
虚空を超えて行け
Go beyond the empty void
見違えていく君の指から今
Right now, from your fingers that look so different
手を放す
I let go of your hand
はい、続いてはねこたかです。
Alright, next up is Nekotaka.
よろしくお願いいします。
We look forward to working with you.
お二人はどういう関係なの？
What kind of relationship do you two have?
パーティ仲間です。
We're party buddies.
パーティ？！
Party?!
よくルイの家で勝手にパーティ開催してます。
We often host parties at Lui's house without asking.
勝手に？！
Without asking?!
人のお家で勝手にパーティはしないと思うんですけども。
Normally, you wouldn't host a party at someone's house without asking...
いやいや、そうなんですけど。
No, no, that's true, but...
最初私もすごい驚いたんですが、最近ではもう私から
At first, I was really surprised too, but lately I've been...
「次いつパーティ？」って言うくらいには虜になっちゃってますね。
asking, "When's the next party?" I've completely fallen for it.
これはねこまたくんの策略かな？
Is this Nekomata-kun's strategy?
こうなると思ってました。
I knew it would turn out like this.
フブさんも今度どうですか、パーティ？
Fubu-san, how about you join us next time for a party?
パーティっていうのは...私も行っていいのかな？
A party...? Is it okay if I go too?
ぜひぜひ！
By all means!
あ、やっぱりねこまたくんが許可下ろすんだね。
Ah, so Nekomata-kun is the one who gives permission.
楽しそうですね。
It sounds like fun.
ポルさんもぜひ！
Pol-san, you too!
あ、じゃ、この後あたりにでも行きましょうか、ポルさんね！
Oh, then shall we go after this, Pol-san?
お、俺？鷹嶺くんが苦笑いしてるんだけど。
Me? Takane-kun is dryly laughing here...
なんか勝手に決められちゃいました。
Somehow, they just decided it without me.
そんなお二人にはですね、かっこよさが詰まったダークチックな曲を披露していただきます！
For the two of you, we will have you perform a cool, dark-themed song!
闇堕ちしてるじゃないか！
You guys have fallen to the dark side!
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
でもねこたかならではの低音を活かしたかっこいいパフォーマンスをしますので、楽しみに！
But we'll put on a cool performance making the most of Nekotaka's deep vocals, so look forward to it!
はい！それではスタンバイ、おねがいします！
Alright! Please standby!
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, we'll do our best.
にゃあ、仲が良そうで、いいですね。
Wow, they seem to get along so well, it's nice.
ま、ぶっちゃけあれは鷹嶺くんもまんざらでもなさそうだよね。
Well, honestly, it seems Takane-kun doesn't mind it either.
そうですね。我々もパーティーに混ざっていいみたいですから。
That's true. It seems we're welcome to join the party too.
なんかルイさんの作るポテトサラダが絶品らしいので。
Apparently, the potato salad made by Lui-san is exquisite.
お、なんか詳しいね。
Oh, you seem well-informed.
あ、まあまあまあまあ！
Ah, well, well, well, well!
ということで、スタンバイができたみたいですね！
And with that, it seems they are ready!
なんか、隠し事か？
Wait, is there a secret?
あ、いいえいいえいいえ！
Ah, no, no, no!
それでは参りましょう。ねこたかで、フィクサー！
Then let's begin. "Fixer" by Nekotaka!
今日までの記憶の全部を
All the memories up until today,
消してしまう時まで眠れない
I can't sleep until the moment they're all erased.
あしたから生きていく自分の
I desperately want a substitute for myself
身代わりが欲しくてたまらない
to go on living starting tomorrow.
大丈夫と言わせて
Let me say "It's alright,"
後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
and won't you let me blame it on you later?
今更意味ないから後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
Since it's too late anyway, won't you let me blame it on you later?
出来ない約束をとうとうと溢れる
Broken promises overflowing endlessly...
一言一言ばかりに脳を奪われるくらい
To the point where my brain is overtaken by each and every word
意味を成さない 何も出来ない
It makes no sense, I can do nothing
見えない 逃げたい 飛びたい やめたい 逸らせない
I can't see, I want to run, I want to fly, I want to stop, I can't look away
だから
So...
沈め 沈め
Sink, sink...
這い上がれないほどまで
To the point where you can't climb back up
飽きるまで
Until you grow tired of it...
落とせ 落とせ
Let it fall, let it fall...
救い垂らす時まで
until a saving hand is extended
嘘味の粒々を喉から締め出した悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
I crush the particles of lie-flavored taste, along with the screams choked out of my throat
笑顔が下手なばっかで知ったような口振りに沿ってやり過ごす
Since I'm bad at smiling, I get by following familiar, knowing words
なりたくなかった
I didn't want to become like this
今日役立つ眠たい眠たい理想で救われることを待つ
Waiting to be saved by a sleepy, sleepy ideal that serves its purpose today
一番目は「はい」の口で言う
The first thing I say is "Yes" with my mouth...
力強く固く痛く噛み締めて
clenching my teeth strongly, firmly, and painfully
死んでしまえ
Just die...
しまえ
die!
この先も過去も知らず
Without knowing the future or the past
嫌いなら
If you hate it...
壊せ 壊せ
destroy it, destroy it
どうせなら加害者になればいい
You might as well become the perpetrator
食べきれない苛立ちも
Both the frustration I can't swallow down...
何も生まれない悲しみも
and the sorrow that births nothing...
味気なくて吐き出す前にもう
It's tasteless, so before spitting it out...
もう次を歌え
sing the next part already!
沈め 沈め
Sink, sink...
落とせ 落とせ
Let it fall, let it fall...
どうせなら踊り踊れ
If you're going to do it, dance, dance!
灰色になり切る前に打ち鳴らせ
Strike a beat before you turn completely gray
変われ 変われ
Change, change
眠り落ちる時まで
until the moment you fall asleep
どうせなら奪え 奪え
If you're going to do it, snatch it away, snatch it away
飼い慣らした嘘暴いて
expose the lies you've tamed
煮え滾る頭に過ぎった虚像を
The phantom that crossed my boiling mind...
見ていた
I was watching it
自分を見ていた
I was looking at myself
続いては、ルイなでのお二人です
Next up is the duo, RuiNade!
よろしくお願いします
We look forward to working with you!
元気がいいなぁ
They're so energetic!
また言ってる、また
There you go saying that again.
お二人は先輩と後輩なんだよね
You two are senior and junior, right?
よく話すの？
Do you talk often?
はい、よくご飯に行ったりしてます
Yes, we often go out to eat together.
お、ご飯！いいな
Oh, meals! That's nice.
何食べてるの？
What do you eat?
主に、しゃぶしゃぶですかね
Mainly shabu-shabu, I think!
しゃぶしゃぶか
Shabu-shabu, huh?
一緒の鍋をつつく関係、これいいね
Sharing a hot pot together, that's a great relationship!
はい！
Yes!
実は、ポルさんに相談がありまして
Actually, I have a concern I want to consult Polka-san about...
ポルさんに相談...？
Consultation with Polka-san...?
ルイ先輩はいつまで経っても私の、お母さんになってくれないんですよ！
No matter how much time passes, Rui-senpai won't become my mom!
ルイ先輩がお母さんになってくれない？
Rui-senpai won't become your mom?
先輩をお母さんにする...？
Making your senior your mom...?
私はいつだって優しいお母さんになってくださる方々を募集してます！よろしくお願いします！
I am always looking for people who will be a kind mom to me! Please apply!
なんでお母さんになってあげないの、逆に？
Why don't you become her mom, then?
いや、なんか、かなでは「娘」って感じがしないというか
Well, Kanade doesn't really feel like a "daughter" to me...
娘になったら、手がかかりすぎて、ちょっと責任持てないなーって
If she became my daughter, she'd require way too much work, and I couldn't take that responsibility.
親戚ポジションでいいかなって
So maybe an "aunt/relative" position is better.
あ、結構壮大な
Oh, it's quite a grand scheme.
音乃瀬君は、他にもママがいるの？
Otonose-kun, do you have other moms too?
もちろん、もちろん！
Of course, of course!
じゃあ要らないでしょ！何で欲しいの？
Then you don't need one! Why do you want another?
頼れる人は一杯いた方がいいじゃないですか！逆にポルさん、お父さんになってくれませんか？
Isn't it better to have as many people to rely on as possible! Polka-san, won't you become my dad instead?
お父さん？
Dad?
お父さん！？
Dad!?
どうですか？
What do you think?
いや、その意見は「お父さん（通さん）」ってな！
No, I can't "pass" on that opinion, dad!
はい、え、というわけでね。ルイなでにはこのあと、「名前のない怪物」を披露していただきます！
Alright, well... next, RuiNade will perform "Namae no Nai Kaibutsu"!
かなで：はい。/ ポルカ：なんでこの曲選んだの？
Kanade: Yes. / Polka: Why did you choose this song?
ルイ：いや、それはすぐ、すぐいけるんだ、そうやって。
Lui: Well, we can get right into it like that.
ルイ：え、私がですね、エゴイストが大好きなんで、その中でもこの曲がすごい大好きなんですけど、
Lui: I really love EGOIST, and among their songs, I especially love this one.
ルイ：奏の初めての歌ってみたがこの曲で、いつか一緒に歌いたいなと思ってこの曲にしました。
Lui: Kanade's first cover song was this one, so I chose it because I wanted to sing it with her someday.
かなで：嬉しい。
Kanade: I'm so happy.
フブキ：それではですね、お二人ともスタンバイお願いします。
Fubuki: Now then, both of you, please get on standby.
ルイ・かなで：はい、よろしくお願いします。
Lui & Kanade: Sure, we'll do our best.
ポルカ：なんか、はちゃめちゃな子だね。
Polka: She's quite a wild kid, isn't she?
フブキ：はい、ですね。なんかよく月曜日に現実を突きつけたりしてるみたいですよ。
Fubuki: Yes, indeed. Apparently, she often slaps people with reality on Mondays.
ポルカ：ああ、罪深い。
Polka: Ah, how sinful.
ポルカ：クソガキだ。/ フブキ：クソガキですね、はい。
Polka: She's a brat. / Fubuki: A brat indeed, yes.
フブキ：ま、しかし歌で魅せてくれるので、ギャップ萌えしてる人も多いんじゃないかなと思います。
Fubuki: But since she captivates us with her singing, I think many people love the gap.
ポルカ：鷹嶺くんも歌うとかっこいいのに、なんかポンコツだからね。
Polka: Lui-kun is also really cool when singing, but usually quite clumsy.
フブキ：そうですね。ま、ギャップがあるお二人って感じじゃないでしょうかね。
Fubuki: Indeed. So they're a duo with great gaps, wouldn't you say?
フブキ：はい、それでは参りましょう。ルイナデで「名前のない怪物」。
Fubuki: All right, let's begin. LuiNade with "Namae no Nai Kaibutsu".
御伽話は
The fairy tales
さっき死んだみたい
seem to have just died.
煉瓦の病棟で
In the brick ward,
うまく歌えなくて
I couldn't sing well.
霧に煙る夜
On a night shrouded in fog,
浮かべ赤い月
a red moon floats.
ほらみて 私を
Look at me...
目を逸らさないで
Don't look away.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born inside black iron bars.
悪意の代償を支払え 望むがままにお前に
Pay the price of malice, just as you desire.
さあ 怯えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
Now, let's fear justice, destroying before being destroyed.
因果の代償を払い
Paying the price of karma,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, monster without a name.
耳鳴りがしてる
My ears are ringing,
鉄条網うるさくて
the barbed wire is so noisy.
思い出せないの
I can't remember
あの日の旋律
the melody of that day.
雨はまだ止まない
The rain still hasn't stopped,
何も見えないの
I can't see anything.
ほらみて こんなに
Look, I have grown
大きくなったの
so big now.
黒い雨 降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Make black rain fall from this sky, I am unwanted.
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛す同罪の傍観者達に
A cracked neurosis to the beloved, equally guilty onlookers.
さあ 今ふるえ正義を
Now, brandish your justice,
消せない傷抱きしめて
embrace the unerasable wounds.
この身体を受け入れ
Accepting this body,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, monster without a name.
ああ
Ah...
神ハ告ゲル
God foretells...
眞ノ世界ヲ
the true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Inside the black iron bars...
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born into this world,
悪意の代償を願え
desiring the price of malice.
望むがままにお前に
Just as you wish, to you...
さあ 与えよう 正義を
Come, let me give you justice.
壊して 壊される前に保存
Destroy it, before you are destroyed.
因果の代償を払い
Pay the price of karma,
報いよ 名もなき怪物
and receive your retribution, nameless monster!
黒い雨 降らせこの空保存
Make the black rain fall from this sky.
私は望まれないもの
I am an unwanted being.
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracked neurosis,
愛す同罪の傍観者達に保存
to the beloved bystanders of equal guilt...
さあ 今ふるえ 正義を
Come, brandish your justice now!
消せない傷を抱きしめて
Embracing the wounds that can't be erased,
この身体を受け入れ
accepting this body,
共に行こう 名もない怪物
let's go together, nameless monster!
さて、ここからは、楠木ともりが
鷹嶺ルイ生誕記念グッズをご紹介！
Now, from here on, Tomori Kusunoki will introduce
Takane Lui's Birthday Celebration Goods!
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド！
キラキラなラメ入りアクリルスタンドがとってもおしゃれな一品。
First, the Glitter Acrylic Stand!
A glittering, glitter-filled acrylic stand that is incredibly stylish.
光を浴びるたびに、きめ細かなラメが
キラキラと輝きを放ちます。
Each time it catches the light,
the fine glitter sparkles brilliantly.
光り輝くアクリルスタンドで、
あなたの生活も更に明るくなるでしょう。
With this shining acrylic stand,
your daily life is sure to become even brighter.
ロック風パーカー！イベントやライブで着るだけでなく、
日常にも溶け込むロック風パーカー。
Next, the Rock-style Hoodie!
Not just for events and concerts, it blends perfectly into everyday life.
前にジップがついているので、部屋着でも
普段着でも使いやすい！ヘビロテ間違いなし！
With a front zipper, it's easy to wear as loungewear
or casual clothing! A guaranteed daily favorite!
ゆるかわバケットハット！
つくねとつみれがワンポイントになっていて、シンプルおしゃかわ。
The Cute Bucket Hat!
Featuring Tsukune and Tsumire as accents, it's simple yet stylishly cute.
普段使いしやすいデザインで、手軽におしゃれ度アップ！
With an easy-to-wear daily design,
it effortlessly upgrades your style!
カジュアル、ストリート、古着MIX、
きれいめカジュアルのハズしアイテムなど、幅広いスタイルにマッチします。
It matches a wide range of styles, from casual, street,
thrift-mix, to a relaxed accent for smart-casual.
「え？」Tシャツ！
ルイ姉でお馴染みのセリフ「え？」をモチーフにネタTとして堂々発売！
The "Huh?" T-Shirt!
Emblazoned with Lui-nee's signature catchphrase, "Huh?",
it's proudly released as a joke tee!
どんなコーディネートにも合う白で、夏は単体で、
冬はパーカーと合わせてインナーとして、一年を通して使えます。
In versatile white, it can be worn on its own in summer,
or layered under a hoodie in winter all year round.
全部セットは数量限定もアリ！
The Full Set is also available in limited quantities!
鷹嶺ルイ直筆サイン
＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード特典！
Bonus: Hand-signed autograph by Takane Lui
& a foil-stamped printed message postcard!
hololive公式ECサイトへ急げ！
Hurry over to the official Hololive Online Shop!
今だけ！
For a limited time only!
続いてはミオルイです！保存
Next up is Mio-Lui!
よろしくお願いします！
We look forward to working with you!
なかなかの、この二人っていうのは、
珍しいよね。
It's quite rare to see the two of you
paired up like this, isn't it?
そう、ですかね？ / そう、ですかねー？うふふ。
Do you think so? / Really? Hehehe.
結構、あの、お話はしたり、仲良いんですよ。 / はい、そうなんです。
Actually, we talk a lot and are quite close. / Yes, that's right.
うーん、何について話してる？
Hmm, what do you guys talk about?
ええ、主に、まあ私がそもそもミオしゃの歌が
本当に大好きで、
Well, mainly... I absolutely love Mio-sha's singing
in the first place,
よく歌のお話をしたりとか、 / 言ってくれてる。
so we talk about singing a lot. / She always says that.
あとは個人的に私の悩みを聞いてもらったりとか
してますね。はい。
And on a personal level, she listens to my worries. Yes.
あぁ、頼りがいあるからね。 / そうなんですよ。
Ah, because she's very reliable. / That's right.
じゃ、その何というか、特別なエピソードとか、
あったりする？
So, do you have any special stories together?
特別なエピソードっていうと、私がちょっと、
しょぼんとした時があったんですけど、
Speaking of special stories,
there was a time when I was feeling a bit down,
その時にパーティーを開いてくれまして、 / パーティーがね、うん。
and she threw a party for me. / A party, indeed.
その時にミオしゃが花束をプレゼントしてくれたんですよ。保存
At that time, Mio-sha gave me a bouquet as a present.
覚えてる？ / 覚えてる覚えてる！ルイの色のね、花束をね。保存
Do you remember? / I remember, I remember!
A bouquet in Lui's colors.
そう、ルイカラーのあの花束をプレゼントしてくれて、
それが、
Yes, she gave me a bouquet in Lui's colors, and...
花瓶も持ってたもんね。 / そう、花瓶も！
I brought a vase too. / Yes, a vase too!
それがすっごい綺麗で、曇ってた心が
一瞬にして晴れましたね。はい。保存
It was so beautiful, my gloomy heart cleared up in an instant. Yes.
うわぁー。 / あぁ、素敵だね。
Wow... / Ah, that's wonderful.
大神さんはよく、花とか買うの？
Mio, do you often buy flowers?
あ、はい。お花すごい大好きで、
Oh, yes. I absolutely love flowers.
あの、うちも落ち込んだ時とかにね、
あの、花を買う時結構あるんですけど、
When I'm feeling down myself,
I quite often buy flowers,
猫が食べちゃうんでね、まあ、あまり買わないんですけど。保存
but since my cats might eat them,
I don't buy them very often.
そうですね、猫ね。
That's true, cats.
さっき聞き逃してたけど、
君たちもよくパーティーするんだね。保存
I missed this earlier,
but you guys throw parties often too, huh?
そうですね。まあでも、おかゆと同じパーティーです。保存
We do. But it's the same party Okayu goes to.
そうですね。あの、私もよく実は参加させて
いただいております。
Indeed. Actually, I also participate quite often.
さっき隠してたのって、白上も参加してるってこと？
What you were hiding earlier was that
you're participating too, Shirakami?
あ、そうですね、あの、ミオさんのオムライスと
ルイさんのポテトサラダはもう、本当にめちゃめちゃ絶品なんです。めちゃめちゃ美味しい。
Oh, yes. Mio's omelette rice and Lui's potato salad
are absolutely exquisite. So delicious!
いや、ちょっと収拾つかなくなりそうなので、
スタンバイお願いします！保存
Well, it seems things are getting a bit out of hand,
so please standby!
はーい、よろしくお願いします！またパーティーしようねー！
Sure! We look forward to it! Let's party again soon!
あ、なんか作ったりしてるの？パーティーで
Ah, do you make anything at parties?
いやいや、私はあの食べる専門ですね
No, I specialize in eating.
食べる専門？
An eating specialist?
はい
Yes.
あぁ、甘やかされてるね
Ah, you're quite spoiled.
そうですね。あ、ポルさんも一度いかがですか？
That's right. Polka, why don't you try it too?
ううん
No...
ポルさんも甘えたいってこと？
Are you saying Polka should be spoiled too?
それはちょっと...
Well, that's...
え？
Huh?
それでは参りましょう！美音ルイで「Beat Eater」
Well then, let's get started! MioLui with "Beat Eater"!
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I've realized I'm rollin' now
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
分かってんだ 魅せられたからって
I understand, even if I'm fascinated
雑な罠に嵌まるつもりなど無い
I have no intention of falling into cheap traps
当たり前が止まんない 怖いな
The ordinary won't stop, it's scary
もどかしさも正しい命題
Even frustration is a correct proposition
ハロー 湧いてくる束の間の自信心
Hello, a fleeting sense of confidence rises
そこからはどう見えてる？ tell me tell me
How does it look from where you are? Tell me, tell me
どれだけ僕を救ってくれるの
Just how much will you save me?
反響していく声 加速して
The echoing voice is accelerating
始まりは何処から？
Where did it all begin?
それも容赦無い力
That, too, is a relentless power
身体を支配している 満ち足りた意欲
Controlling my body, a satisfying desire
darlin' darlin' タフに噛んでいくスタイル
Darlin', darlin', a style of chewing through it toughly
まにまに幕を上げるのさ
As we please, we raise the curtain
何がどうなったって不思議じゃない
No matter what happens, it's no wonder
振りを増し答えになって響き出すよ
Exaggerating gestures to become the answer, echoing out
come over 消えていかない感覚
Come over, a sensation that won't fade
あくまでも踊ってたいだけ
I just want to dance to the very end
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I've realized I'm rollin' now
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばい何となくなのに
Oh no, even though it's just somehow
見透かされてんの鬼
Being completely seen through like an ogre
予想よりうねって長い傾向
A longer and more winding trend than expected
不確かなものに囲まれてんだね
We're surrounded by uncertain things, aren't we?
そこらじゅうに転がってる惰弱
Weakness rolling around everywhere
妄想だって思いのほか重要
Even delusions are unexpectedly important
心に逆らう外れた振る舞い
Deviant behaviors going against the heart
早まったのさ 引くに引けない様相
I acted too hastily, in a state where I can't back down
ほら手に入れた座標を打ち込め
Look, plug in the coordinates you obtained
姿を写してアブラカダブラ
Reflecting the figure, abracadabra
道は分かれてたんだ
The path had parted
それも遠い所から
And from a distant place, too
全て間違いじゃない悲しみ方
A way of grieving that is not entirely wrong
darlin' darlin' 満更でもない
Darlin', darlin', not so bad after all
まにまに塗り直すのさ
As we please, we repaint it
今になればいつだって構わない
Now, it doesn't matter when it is
色を変え答えになって溢れ出すよ
Changing colors, becoming the answer, spilling over
come over 消えていかない感覚
Come over, a sensation that won't fade
まだまだ足りてないみたい
It seems like it's still not enough
重なり合う光 痛みに寄り添う
Overlapping lights cozy up to the pain
何処にも消えないで欲しい
I hope you won't disappear anywhere
留まる濃い深い重心頼り
Relying on a dense, deep center of gravity that stays
傷付くこともある
There are times when we get hurt
darlin' darlin' タフに噛んでいくスタイル
Darlin', darlin', a style of chewing through it toughly
まにまに体現するのさ
As we please, we embody it
何がどうなったって不思議じゃない
No matter what happens, it's no wonder
振りを増し答えになって響き出すよ
Exaggerating gestures to become the answer, echoing out
come over 消えていかない感覚
Come over, a sensation that won't fade
あくまでも踊ってたいだけ
I just want to dance to the very end
気付いたんだ今は rollin'
I've realized I'm rollin' now
止まりたくないんだ no need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばい何となくなのに
Oh no, even though it's just somehow
見透かされてんの鬼
Being completely seen through like an ogre
続いては鷹嶺ルイです！
Up next, we have Takane Lui!
はい、よろしくお願いします
Yes, thank you for having me.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
鷹嶺くんはなんか、うーん、最近ハマってるゲームとかある？
Lui-kun, is there... hmm, any game you're into lately?
ハマってるゲームあります
I do have a game I'm into.
あの、最近ってわけでもないんですけど、事務所に入ってから「ドラゴンクエスト」というゲームに出会いまして
Well, it's not exactly recent, but after joining the agency, I discovered a game called "Dragon Quest."
あー、ドラゴンクエスト！
Oh, Dragon Quest!
ナンバリング1から11までやっていて、派生とかもあるので。本当に面白くてですね、大好きです。
I've played from numbered titles 1 to 11, and there are spin-offs too. It's really interesting, I love it.
そのドラクエの、どんなところが魅力？
So, what's the appeal of Dragon Quest?
魅力、たくさんあるんですけど、本当に人生の教科書だなって思うことが結構多くて
There are many appealing points, but I often think it's truly a textbook for life.
もちろん悲しいこともあるんですけど、それを仲間たちと支え合って前に進んでいくパワーと
Of course, there are sad moments, but the power of supporting each other with companions and moving forward...
ナンバリングが進んでいくにつれて分かる真実とかがあったりとか
...and the truths that are revealed as the numbering progresses...
長年愛されてる理由が詰まってるなって感じますね、はい
...I feel it really contains the reasons why it's been loved for so long. Yes.
あ、じゃ、ゲーム以外も...
Ah, so besides games...
え、なんかドラクエのそういうイベントとか行ったりしてるの？
Have you been going to any Dragon Quest events or things like that?
はい、行ってますね。ドラクエのテーマパークだったりとか、
Yes, I have! Like Dragon Quest theme parks,
あとは限定ショップに行ったりとか。
and limited-time shops.
あとはアニメもあるので、ファンの方と同時視聴とか、したりしてましたね。はい。
There's also an anime, so I've done watch parties with fans.
充実してんなあ！
You've been keeping busy!
はい、充実してます。
Yes, I've been making the most of it!
そんなドラクエ大好きな鷹嶺ルイさんには、
For Takane Lui-san, who loves Dragon Quest so much,
これからアニメ『ドラゴンクエスト ダイの大冒険』の初代オープニング、
she will now perform the first opening theme of the anime, "Dragon Quest: The Adventure of Dai"...
『生きるをする』を披露していただきます！
..."Ikiru o Suru"!
それは楽しみだ。/ 楽しみですね。
I'm looking forward to that. / It's so exciting!
はい。特別な演出にも注目してくれると嬉しいです！
Yes! I hope you'll pay attention to the special stage effects too!
はい！それではスタンバイ、お願いします！
Alright! Please get ready on standby!
はい、よろしくお願いします。/ お願いしまーす！
Okay, thank you! / Please do!
いや、はまるものがあるっていうのは、いいよね。/ いいですよねー！
It's so nice to have something you're deeply passionate about. / It really is!
何やらこの曲、歌ってほしいというリクエストもかなり多かったみたいですよ。
Apparently, there were tons of requests for her to sing this song!
あ、ってことは、みんな待望ってわけだね。/ ですねー！
So it's highly anticipated by everyone then! / Exactly!
あ、それでは、スタンバイができたみたいなので、行きましょう！
Oh, looks like she's ready. Let's get to it!
鷹嶺ルイさんで、『生きるをする』です。どうぞ！
Here is Takane Lui with "Ikiru o Suru"! Please enjoy!
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
Loving myself all the way through,
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, is it okay to still believe in it?
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter where this journey takes me.
あれ、いつからだ？本音が弱音になったな
Oh, when did it start? My true feelings became weaknesses.
逃げないことが強さになったな
Not running away became my definition of strength.
なあ、見つからない？自信じゃなく自分自身
Hey, can't you find it? Not self-confidence, but myself.
きっとまだ探せてない忘れものがあるはず
There must be something forgotten that I haven't found yet.
ずっとまだ伝えてない伝えたい言葉
The words I want to convey that I still haven't said.
見ててくれるなら魅せてみせるのに
If you would watch me, I'd captivate you, and yet...
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
Loving myself all the way through,
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, is it okay to still believe in it?
くすぶるのは、ちゃんと燃えたからだ
Smoldering only happens because it burned properly.
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter where this journey takes me.
ただ、目を見開いて夢を見る
I'll just open my eyes wide and dream.
夢を知る
I know the dream.
よう、生きてるかい？
Yo, are you living?
本当の強さ きみだけが分かってればいいのさ
True strength, as long as you're the only one who knows it, that's enough.
逃げたり傷ついた数だけ居場所は増えたりする
The places where you belong only increase by the times you ran and got hurt.
見ててくれ 姿じゃなく生き方を
Watch me. Not my appearance, but how I live.
僕が僕を愛し抜かなきゃ
I have to love myself all the way through.
終わらない聖者の交信、悲しみの縫い目に投げキッス
Sending a blow kiss to the seams of sadness on this endless saints' communion.
どこへ向かう旅でも行こうぜ
Let's go, no matter where this journey takes us.
まだ手を取り合って
Still holding hands together.
脳、映像、スカイはグレー、夜を駆ける
Brain, images, the sky is gray, running through the night.
束の間、終幕、裏切りは愛のおまけ
A brief moment, the final act, betrayal is just a bonus of love.
かさぶたになる日々 美しくはないのさ
The days turning into scabs aren't beautiful at all.
腰に巻いた正義の切れ味はどんなだ
How sharp is the justice strapped to your waist?
僕らは違う痛みを生きる
We live through different kinds of pain.
勇敢でいたい、立ち向かいたい
I want to be brave, I want to face it.
眠っていたストーリーを凄いスピードで覚ましたいやいやいや
I want to wake up my sleeping story at an incredible speed.
僕が僕を愛せる強さを
The strength that allows me to love myself,
かなり愛してもいいか？
is it okay to cherish it deeply?
くすぶるのは、燃えカスになるまで
Smoldering on until it turns to ashes.
どこへ向かう旅だっていいさ いいのさ
No matter where this journey takes us, it's fine, it's okay.
ただ、目を見開いて息をする
I'll just open my eyes wide and breathe.
生きるをする
I am living.
これでまー、食らえ！
Take this!
続いてはおにかんです。
Next up is Onikan.
よろしくお願いします！
Nice to meet you!
前回に引き続きもうお二人は仲が良いね。
Continuing from last time, you two are still close.
はい、仲良いですよ。
Yes, we are really close.
相性もぴったりだ。
Your chemistry is perfect.
なきりさんは今日、シュークリーム食べた？
Nakiri-san, did you eat cream puffs today?
今日はね、まだ食べてないんですよ。でも、お弁当食べました！
I haven't eaten any today. But I did eat my bento!
お弁当ね、美味しいのあったからね。
Ah, the bento had some really tasty stuff in it.
美味しかったです。
It was delicious!
ねー、私たちも後で食べましょうね、ポルさん。ね？
Let's eat ours later too, Pol-san, okay?
そうだね、お腹ペコペコだからね。
Yeah, since we're starving!
そして何やらお二人は、私たちMCに聞きたいことがあるらしいですよ。
And it seems they have something they want to ask us hosts.
はい、何何？
Really? What is it?
いや、こうやってミュージックガーデンやってますけど、お二人はなんか歌いたい！ってなってないですか？歌いてー！みたいな。
We're doing Music Garden like this, but don't you two ever feel like, "I want to sing!" or "I really wanna sing!"?
え？歌いたい？ま、多少ね。
Huh? Sing? Well, a little bit.
口ずさんだり、体動いたりするけどね。
We hum along and move our bodies, sure.
でも、MCだから、ね？
But we're the hosts, right?
ねー、はい、MCなので。
Right, yes, since we are the hosts.
じゃあ、ホントは歌って踊りたいってことでいいですか？
So in truth, you really do want to sing and dance, right?
いや、皆さんのいいパフォーマンス見てたらねー。
Well, watching everyone's great performances makes us...
じゃあ、じゃあね、踊って歌いましょうか！はい、じゃあ立っていただいて。
In that case, let's sing and dance then! Okay, please stand up.
いや、私はいいよ...
No, no, we're fine...
いいから、いいから、立っていただいて。
It's fine, it's fine, please stand up.
あっち側で、衣装を着替えていただいていいですか？
Could you go over there and change into your outfits?
衣装？！はい、すぐ行くすぐ行く、すぐ行って。
Outfits?! Okay, we'll go right now, let's go!
いってらっしゃい。じゃ、スタンバイしに行ってください。
Have fun! Go get on standby.
じゃあね、こちらで一旦CMです。
Well then, let's take a quick commercial break.
あ、それ私のセリフ！
Ah, that was my line!
お、準備できたかな？大丈夫かな？着替えて...
Oh, is the preparation ready? Are they okay? After changing...
じゃあね、私たちも行きましょうか。行きましょう、行きましょう。
Well then, shall we go too? Let's go, let's go.
じゃあ、ポルさん、カンペ読んでください。
Well then, Pol-san, please read the cue card!
え？え？それでは聞いてください。おにかんプラスフブポルで「チャンカパーナ」
Eh? Eh? Well then, please listen. Onikan plus FubuPol singing "Chankapana"!
深夜バスで君を見た 息を呑むよな黒髪
Riding the midnight bus you're catching my eye, with silky hair moving so elegantly
行き先は違うけれど オレは迷わず飛び乗る
You might be heading to a different place, but fate is calling me, I go after you
一人じゃ悲しすぎる夜さ 誰かと話したかった
All by myself, it's too hard to bear this lonely night, I just needed someone to hold me tight
君もうれしそうで どちらからともなく 手を握る
I see that you're smiling with me, as if this all was meant to be, now we're holding hands
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapana Chankapana
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
Drives me crazy how much I'm aching for your love
もう ジン ジン 燃えている 身体は止まらない
Burning Jin Jin heated up for you, my body can't escape your body
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapana Chankapana
頷いた君 抱きしめた
You say yes, and right there I'm holding you so right
恥らうその瞳 狂ってしまいそう
When you look so shy behind those eyes, it drives me crazy
夜の吐息のなか
In the sigh of the night
チャンカパーナ
Chankapana
バスを捨てて二人は 眠れる場所を探した
Leaving the bus behind, we looked for a place to sleep
うやうやしく服を脱ぎ ベッドに滑り込む花
Gently taking off our clothes, a flower sliding into bed
この世にも天使がいたのさ その肌に触れたんだ
There really was an angel in this world, I touched her skin
「恋って好き」なんて悪戯に言うから 舞い上がる
When you playfully say "I love you," my heart flutters
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapana Chankapana
人生で一番美味しいもの
The most delicious thing in my life
そう ナン ナン 何度だって 君を抱いていたい
Yes, over and over again, I want to hold you tight
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapana Chankapana
まだまだ君が足りないよ
I still can't get enough of you
露なその果実 狂ってしまいそう
Your exposed fruit drives me crazy
夜よ醒めないでくれ チャンカパーナ
Please don't wake up, night. Chankapana
美しい恋にする
I'll make this a beautiful love
美しい恋にするよ
I will make this a beautiful love
美しい恋にするから
Since I'll make this a beautiful love
約束するよ、チャンカパーナ
I promise you, Chankapana
美しい恋にするから 約束するよ、チャンカパーナ
I'll make this a beautiful love. I promise, Chankapana.
月がふたりを探すから
Because the moon is looking for the two of us,
今夜 世界から身を隠そう
tonight, let's hide from the world.
覗いたその肌は
The skin peeking out...
褐色の葡萄だね
is like amber-colored grapes.
Baby チャン チャン チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapana Chankapana
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so much it hurts.
もう ジン ジン 燃えている
I'm already burning, tingling all over,
身体は止まらない
my body won't stop.
Baby チャン チャン チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby Chan Chan Chankapana Chankapana
オレの腕にしがみついた
Clinging to my arm,
華奢なその肩に
those delicate shoulders
狂ってしまいそう
are going to drive me crazy.
夜の吐息のなか
In the sighs of the night...
チャンカパーナ
Chankapana!
Project "L"
[Title: Project "L"]
鷹嶺ルイ 1st Album
[Takane Lui 1st Album]
Liberty
[Takane Lui 1st Album: Liberty]
鷹嶺ルイ生誕3Dライブを見ている諸君、お初にお目にかかる。
To everyone watching Takane Lui's Birthday 3D Live, pleased to meet you.
私はゼロ。黒の騎士団の総帥にして、世界への反逆者。
I am Zero. Leader of the Black Knights, and a rebel against the world.
ここまでのMパートではどうだったかな？ 大いに盛り上がったことだろう。
How did you like the music section so far? I am sure you were highly excited.
ほう... だが、まだ足りないな。
Hoh... But that is still not enough.
諸君らなら、まだまだ盛り上がれるはずだ。鷹嶺ルイの歌によってな！
You all should be able to get much more excited... through Takane Lui's song!
ルルーシュ・ヴィ・ブリタニアが命じる。
Lelouch vi Britannia commands you.
鷹嶺ルイよ、コードギアスの主題歌メドレーで、さらに盛り上げるのだ！
Takane Lui, fire them up even more with a Code Geass theme song medley!
Yes, Your Highness.
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
It feels like it could change myself, and even the world,
瞬間は いつもすぐそばに...
that moment is always right by my side...
隠せぬ苛立ちと
Staring at my undisguisable frustration...
立ち尽くす自分を見つめ
and how I just stand there frozen.
迷いながら 悩みながら
Getting lost, worrying...
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
and regretting—it's okay to make your choice then.
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
With just one word you gave me,
戸惑いは消え去り
my hesitation vanished completely.
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に
Into my empty room,
光が射した
a beam of light shone through.
見上げた大空が
The vast sky I looked up at
青く澄み切って行く
is clearing up into a beautiful blue.
閉ざした窓を
I decided...
開く事を決めた
to open the closed window.
自分を 世界さえも
It feels like it could change myself,
変えてしまえそうな
and even the world,
瞬間は いつもすぐそばに...
that moment is always right by my side...
夢見てた 夢
The dream I used to dream,
果て無き遠く
infinitely far away,
乾いた日々の 空色 手の中
the sky color of dry days, held in my hands...
In the sky-colored hands of dry days,
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
trial and error in the equally spaced sounds,
時間・間隔の無い空間 ah
in a space with no time or intervals, ah...
等身大 音をたてて
making life-sized sounds,
僕の顔、造って行く
I build up my own face.
キレイに、片方だけ。
Beautifully, only on one side.
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ吼えよと吼え
Though I walk a path of beasts, cry out like a roaring lion.
茜射す空の 彼方にまほろば
Beyond the crimson-tinted sky lies a peaceful land.
幽囚の孤濁に 彷徨う青春は
Youth wandering in imprisoned solitude,
弱さと怒りが 貌無き敵ですか
are weakness and anger our faceless enemies?
父よ 未だ我は 己を知りがたし
Father, I still find it hard to know myself.
先立つ兄らの
Following the invisible backs
見えない背中を追えば
of my brothers who went before me,
迷いの一夜に明星は誘う
the morning star guides me through a night of doubt.
死して終わらぬ
Even if I yearn
夢を焦がれども
for a dream that doesn't end with death,
確かな君こそ我が命
only you, who are real, are my life.
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Living like a butterfly or flower in the gale-swept wilderness,
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
an illusion blooming alongside eternal spring.
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Even if this body is stained with turbid purity,
心の錦を 信じていてください
please believe in the brocade of my heart.
母よ けして我は 涙を見せねども
Mother, though I will never show my tears,
足下の草に露は消えもせで
the dew on the grass beneath my feet will never fade.
朝も 夜も 恋い焦がれて
Morning and night, yearning with love,
星になるよ 君守る 戦いは 行方知らず
I will become a star to protect you, with no end to this battle in sight.
明日と昨日の 交差点で
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday,
交わらない キミとボク
you and I will never cross paths.
今行くよ ボクは流れ星
I'm on my way now, I am a shooting star.
世界が朽ち果ててても 変わることのないものがある
Even if the world decays, there are things that will never change.
涙をこらえてても 守るべきものが僕らにはある
Even if we hold back our tears, we have things we must protect.
何万年何億年前からのメッセージが体内でうずきだす 鳴り響く
Messages from tens of thousands, hundreds of millions of years ago throb inside me and echo.
しゃがれた声で 明日を呼ぶ 傷だらけの手で 君守る
Calling for tomorrow in a hoarse voice, protecting you with scarred hands.
I continue to fight
見つめ合い 手と手を重ねて ガラス越しのキミとボク
Gazing at each other, hands overlapping, you and I across the glass.
こんなにも側にいるのに
Even though we are so close to each other...
暗い闇を白に染めるよ
I will dye the dark darkness into white.
出口のない 君のもとへ
To you, who are trapped in a place with no exit.
運命を切り裂く 流れ星
A shooting star that tears through destiny.
あふれる君の涙 ボクがいま奪い去る
I will steal away your overflowing tears right now.
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Piecing together mosaic fragments one by one, I draw them out.
あなたがくれた 出会いと別れも
Even the encounters and farewells that you gave me.
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
"It shouldn't be like this," I thought as I fell asleep.
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
When I wake up, it's the same old, unchanging spinning in circles.
意味も無く繰り返し
Repeating meaninglessly.
モザイクカケラ 拾い集めてた「上手く生きる為の術」
The mosaic fragments I gathered were "the art of living well."
歪なそれが美しく見えたんだ
Those distorted pieces looked beautiful to me.
強がりながら 躓きながら選び抜いた道の上で
On the path I chose while acting tough and stumbling along,
剥がれ落ちては 埋まらないカケラ
fragments peel off, leaving gaps that can't be filled.
剥がれ落ちては　埋まらないカケラ
The fragments that flake off and can never be replaced...
鷹嶺ルイ コードギアスシリーズ宣伝アンバサダー就任決定
Takane Lui Appointed as Code Geass Series Promotion Ambassador
詳細は公式XまたはYouTubeチャンネルで
Details on the official X or YouTube channel
はい、ということで特報VTR見ていただきましたけれども
Alright, so you've just watched the special announcement video!
なんと、この、鷹嶺ルイ
And believe it or not, I, Takane Lui...
なんと、なんと！コードギアスアンバサダーに決定しました！
...have indeed been chosen as the Code Geass Ambassador!
いえーい！嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
Yay! I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
もうめちゃくちゃね、コードギアスシリーズ大、大、大、大好きなので
I absolutely love, love, love the Code Geass series,
こんな素晴らしい機会をいただけるの本当に嬉しいでございます。
so I'm truly overjoyed to have such a wonderful opportunity.
皆さんのおかげです、本当にありがとうございます。
It's all thanks to you, thank you so much!
そしてですね、皆さんお気づき、もう気づいてますよね！
Also, as you've probably noticed—actually, you must have!
もうなんと、ルルーシュ役の福山さんが鷹嶺ルイと呼んでいただき、
Jun Fukuyama, the voice of Lelouch, actually said my name,
命じていただきました！本当にすごい！
and gave me an order! It's absolutely incredible!
こんな豪華なことってあるんですか？いや本当にありがとうございます。
How could something so extravagant happen? Thank you so much!
もうコードギアスメドレーでもね、あのバックに、はい、あのコードギアスの
And during the Code Geass medley, in the background,
アニメーションもエンディングと歴代のエンディングとオープニングも流れたということで
they played the previous opening and ending animations!
本当に豪華な仕上がりになっていたんですけども、いかがでしたか？皆さん。
It was such a lavish performance! How did you all like it?
ね？はい、私もめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです、本当にありがとうございます。
Right? I'm so incredibly happy too! Thank you so much!
え、アンバサダーとしてのですね、お仕事はですね、
My duties as an ambassador will include...
え、歌ってみたをあげたりとか、あとは同時視聴をしたりとか、
uploading cover songs, hosting watch-along streams,
あとはそのほか、もろもろ、あのいろいろ盛りだくさんで用意しておりますので、
and many other exciting things we have lined up!
詳細はですね、このあと、コードギアスシリーズの公式YouTubeチャンネルにも投稿されますので、
Details will be posted on the official Code Geass YouTube,
ぜひぜひチェックしてみてください。
so please be sure to check it out!
もちろん私のXでも、え、XやYouTubeチャンネルでも、
Of course, I'll also be sharing updates on my X,
え、詳細をその都度、あの伝えていきますので、
and my YouTube channel as they come up.
え、チャンネル登録、そしてXのフォローもよろしくお願いします。
So please subscribe to my channel and follow me on X!
さて、このあとはですね、新曲を披露させていただきます。よ！
Next up, I will be performing my brand new song!
来ましたよ、私の新曲が。ということで新曲のタイトルはですね、
Here comes my new song! The title of the song is...
ZIG-ZAGという曲になっております。
"ZIG-ZAG"!
ZIG-ZAGというのはですね、トラウマの蔑称になっているんですけども、
"Zig-zag" is actually another term for trauma,
え、そのジグザグ、え、自分の中にあるトラウマと戦って
and this song is about fighting the trauma within yourself,
前を向いていこうというカッコいい、カッコよく前を向いていくという、え、曲になっておりますので、
and moving forward in a cool, stylish way.
ぜひぜひ、え、みんなにもちょっと聴いていただいて、
I hope you all listen to it,
あ、こんなことあるな、私もこんなことあるなと共感していただけたら嬉しいなと思います。
and can relate to it like, "Yeah, I've been there too."
それではじゃあ曲振りは、コードギアスのアンバサダーにもなったということで久々にルルイシュでいきたいと思います。
Since I'm now the ambassador, I'll introduce the song as "Lelou-Lui-sh"!
みんな、準備はいいか？あ、私の準備もいいか？大丈夫か？ということでいきますよ！
Are you guys ready? Am I ready? Let's do this!
ルルイシュ・ヴィ・タカネーリが命ずる。
Lelou-Lui-sh vi Takaneli commands you...
お前たち、新曲を聴け！
Listen to my new song!
ワン、ツー、スリー、フォー
One, two, three, four!
「幸せ」って囁いた問いがラッタッタラッタ
The question whispering "happiness" goes rat-tat-tat-tat
こびり付いて離れんわ駄目だラッタッタラッタ
It clings and won't leave me, it's no use, rat-tat-tat-tat
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember a tasteless, odorless life anymore
忘れたいから歌った馬鹿だラッタッタラッタ
I sang because I wanted to forget, how foolish, rat-tat-tat-tat
恨む事も 憎む事も
Neither holding a grudge nor hating...
賢くない故 出来なかった
...was something I could do, as I'm not that clever.
これが君の結末ならば
If this is how your story ends...
笑ってしまいたいほど
...it makes me want to just laugh it off.
嘘 嘘 嘘嘘嘘
Lies, lies, lies, lies, lies!
嘘つき
Liar.
やだ痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
Oh no, it hurts, hurts, hurts... wishing for a miracle
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌 タチが悪いわ
I'm so sick of this... how nasty of me.
ねえ辛い Lie Lie Lie 否？ おかしいと全部えぐり取って
Hey, does it hurt? Lie, lie, lie, or not? Gouging out everything that feels wrong,
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
call me heartless if you want, say whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのですですでででです
I just want to say bye-bye to my trauma, I really, really do!
私、甘え上手になれなかった 可愛げとかが足りなかった
I couldn't be good at being spoiled, I lacked cuteness
後悔が煩い夜だ
It's a night noisy with regrets
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば きっといいコトあるさと
If I just set the past as the past, they say good things will surely happen
それくらい 百も承知だ ラッタッタ
I'm well aware of that, rat-tat-tat
願う事も 祈る事も 許されないから黒く染めた
Since neither wishing nor praying is allowed, I dyed it black
元の色も思いだせない 絡んだ運命の糸 糸 糸 糸 糸
I can't even remember the original color, the tangled threads of fate
やだ痛い痛い痛いな 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
Oh, it hurts, hurts, hurts, playing the tragic heroine
もう嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 諦めちゃえば？
I hate it, hate it, hate it... why not just give up?
demo aitai aitai na shikou kairo ga konnagaracchatte
But I want to meet, want to meet, my train of thought is tangled up
明日またきっと 壊すけどいいの
I'll surely break it again tomorrow, but that's fine
トラウマさえ愛おしいのです です です です
Even the trauma is precious to me
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I am holding hands with you
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
Just like the two of us back then, knowing nothing
でも分かっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know, that I will wake up soon
それならばいっそ 君の手でそっと...
If so, I'd rather you gently, with your hand...
止め刺して ほら 今今今！
...deliver the final blow, look, now, now, now!
やだ痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
Oh, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping for a bit of a miracle
もう嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 タチが悪いわ
I hate it, hate it, hate it, this is bad
ねえ 辛い Lie Lie Lie 否？ おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, is it painful, or a lie? Gouge out all the strange parts
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me heartless, it's fine, call me whatever you like
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です です です
I want to say bye-bye to the trauma
嘘つき
Liar.
やだ痛い痛い痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって本地
Oh, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping for a bit of a miracle
もう嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 タチが悪いわ
I hate it, hate it, hate it, this is bad
ねえ 辛い Lie Lie Lie 否？ おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, is it painful, or a lie? Gouge out all the strange parts
薄情で結構
Call me heartless, it's fine
楽しくお届けしてきましたミュージックガーデン、あっという間にエンディングのお時間となりました。
The Music Garden we've been happily bringing you has in no time reached the ending.
ポルカちゃん、今日はどうでしたか？
Polka-chan, how was it today?
いやぁ、なんか、今日は私も一緒に歌って踊っちゃったからね！
Well, somehow, I sang and danced along today too!
いつも以上にボルテージが上がっちゃったね。あぁ、あと、もう一時間やる？
My voltage went up even more than usual. Ah, can we do another hour?
やりたいですけど、もうホントに、もっとやりたいんですけどね、グッズ販売とプレミア公開も迫ってますので！
I want to, I really want to do more, but the merchandise sales and premiere are coming up!
あぁ、そっか、そっか。
Ah, I see, I see.
いや、鷹嶺君、今日はてんこ盛りだったね！
Well, Takane-kun, today was packed!
まさか、コードギアス...
I can't believe, Code Geass...
溜めてる、溜めてる
Holding back, holding back.
私もね、早く言いたくて、言いたくてたまらなかったです。
Me too, I wanted to say it so badly, I couldn't wait.
この後グッズ販売と、新曲プレミア公開、そしてメンバーシップ限定配信もありますので、楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです！
After this, we have merch sales, the new song premiere, and a member-only stream, so I hope you enjoy them!
本当にこの後も盛りだくさんだ！改めてお誕生日おめでとうね！
There's really so much more to come! Happy birthday once again!
いや、ありがとうございます。ミュージックガーデン2できて、本当に嬉しいです。
Thank you so much. I'm so glad we could do Music Garden 2.
ポルさんもフブさんも、本当にありがとうございました！
Pol-san, Fubu-san, thank you both so much!
ぜひね、また、またやりたいね！
We should definitely do this again!
まあ、ぜひ、またやりたいですね。
Yes, I'd love to do it again.
よろしくお願いします。
I look forward to it.
せっかくですので、ゲストの皆さんにも感想いただきましょう。
Since they're here, let's get some comments from our guests.
皆さんから何か言いたいことがあるみたいですよ。
It seems they have something they want to say.
ルイ、お誕生日おめでとう！
Lui, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！みんなと歌って踊れて、本当に幸せでした。またコラボしようね！
Thank you so much! I was so happy to sing and dance with everyone. Let's collab again!
はい、では、本当にあっという間ですが、今夜のミュージックガーデンはここまでとなります。ありがとうございました！
All right, it went by so quickly, but that's all for tonight's Music Garden. Thank you so much!
それではまたミュージックガーデン3が叶う日まで、さようなら！
Until the day we can do Music Garden 3, goodbye!
さようなら！
Goodbye!
ラプ、やべえぞ！
Lapu, this is bad!
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
とんでもねえグッズ出るぞ！
Some crazy merch is coming out!
はい？
What?
バカすげえグッズが一気に来るぞ！
A ton of awesome merch is coming all at once!
Tシャツ！
T-shirt!
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド！
Glitter acrylic stand!
ゆるカワバケットハット！
Loose-cute bucket hat!
欲しい！
I want it!
ロックパーカー！
Rock hoodie!
着たい！
I want to wear it!
そして、フルセットには直筆...
And, the full set comes with an autographed...
直筆サイン入りポストカードがつくぞ！
It comes with a handwritten signed postcard!
なんだってーー！
What did you say?!
さらにホロもついてくる
And it also comes with a holographic version!
うおおおおおお！
Uwoooogh!
これは買いでしょう！
This is a must-buy!